Hello, my friends, and welcome again to the complete data structure and algorithms course, this exercise
number 49 asked us to write a function to search for the specific value in linked list recursively.
We have solved this exercise in the previous video and exercise number forty eight and we have seen
this and we have tested it before.
So this is the function that we have created.
Now we are asked to do it the same way, but the same thing, but we are asked to write it recursively.
So all the video and transform this this method into a method that uses recursion.
OK, so weighting your solutions and rating your questions or any recommendations.
So let's begin solving and transforming this search method into a search method that uses recursion.
OK.
Public Boolean search search recursively.
And it took in the same perimeter.
No, no.
And we have index that we are going to search for.
And as I told you, the same as while have a break condition current equal to null, I'm transforming
it into a base case.
So always use base case.
But please go back to the recursion section in order to understand what are the base case and what is
the breaking as condition for that recursion.
If had equal equal to now, then return false.
OK, now if key is presented in good and not, then return true if had.
If I am looking forward to that the hat, I'm looking for a data equal equal to X and it is equal to
the head, then move and return through.
OK.
It's very simple.
If I am looking forward to the first night, if I'm looking for a value that it's stored in the first
node, which is the had.
So if I'm looking for 10, that is stored inside the first thought and that is the case, so it will
return true.
Otherwise, it will search for the other nods in the list.
So but here we are using it without iteration, we are going to use the recursion so recursively.
Search for the remaining list.
OK, return, search for search recursively and had the next.
And what I'm going to make, I'm going to search for the X was here.
I need to search for the eggs and had a dog.
Next, I am moving from the head to the next and next and next and so on until either reaching and null
or either reaching that date.
OK.
Therefore, we have created this search recursively method.
Let's test it in the main.
And exercise here, I'm making exercise.
Forty nine, search for specific
value and being kept less every care, so.
The same way I am copying and pasting.
Ford Foundling it list search recursively.
I pressed the head of the link at least, and the value that I'm going to search for, that's Ron Nancy.
And here we go.
We have value of four found.
Yes, it is true.
OK.
Because there's the hat.
And this is the way that we have searched about a specific value in that injured list using iterative
and recursion.
OK.
I am waiting your questions, your recommendation and I hope your eight hour course.
Five.